BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
[♪ opening theme song playing]
EPISODE 30:
THE HERO OF THE SOUTH
♪
[birds chirping]
[OLD MAN] We have a statue
in dire need of a good polish.
What's the reward?
[OLD MAN] A spell to scratch
the hard-to-reach,
itchy parts on your back.
[OLD MAN] Hmm.
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN FABEL VILLAGE, LOCATED
IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
I guess we're back
to odd jobs, then.
Seems there are rusty statues
of Mr. Himmel in every town.
True! It'll be nice
to use our hands
for more than axe
and staff slinging.
All right. Time to clean!
The statue's made of bronze,
so we can use magic.
You won't have
to lift a single finger.
[STARK] Uh?
[STARK] Uh...
[STARK] That guy isn't Himmel!
[FRIEREN] Is this your
first time seeing him?
That's the Hero of the South.
[BOTH] Hmm.
Though Himmel was the one
who defeated the Demon King,
he was not the only hero.
Dozens of brave souls
made the attempt before him.
But of them all,
the Hero of the South was said
to be humanity's strongest.
[STARK]
That seems a bit extreme.
I'd have to disagree.
In my opinion,
he was worthy of the title.
At the time, a fearsome group
posed a threat to humanity.
The Seven Sages of Destruction.
They controlled
the major regions
around the northern lands.
Despite all our
greatest efforts,
we only managed to defeat
two members of their band.
Of the other five, two vanished.
We assumed they either fled
or tucked themselves away.
Guess one of those was
Aura the Guillotine.
[FRIEREN] The Hero of the South
was powerful enough
to defeat the remaining three.
[children laughing]
His rapid advance was
unlike anything I've ever seen.
In just a year,
he completely annihilated
the Demon King's
front-line troops.
That cleared a pathway
to the very top
of the Northern Plateau,
the heart of the
Demon King's supply route.
♪
That's where he was defeated
by Schlacht the Omniscient,
the Demon King's confidant
who could see a thousand years
into the future,
making him a fearsome foe.
At the hands of Schlacht
and the Seven Sages,
he met his end.
He fought against all seven?
No wonder he kicked the bucket.
[FRIEREN]
It wasn't a quick fight.
He still defeated
three of them, remember?
The battle only ended
when he and Schlacht
took each other's lives.
His valiant efforts that day
liberated many people
in this region
from the tyranny
of the Seven Sages.
It only makes sense
the villagers here
are devoted to him.
Because the Hero
of the South's body
was never recovered,
legend claims he's
still fighting tooth and nail
with Schlacht the Omniscient
to this day.
Though I highly doubt
it's that romantic.
His opponents had a keen taste
for human flesh.
I imagine they ate
every last piece of the hero.
Shall we get the old boy
cleaned up?
[FRIEREN] I refuse.
I cannot defeat the Demon King.
Hmm... I knew that
this would happen.
And I knew I'd never
conjure up the right words
to convince
a complete enigma like you.
You speak
as if you already knew
exactly how
this would play out.
I suppose it seems that way
because I did.
Hmm.
You seem the type
to carefully guard a secret.
[FRIEREN] Hm?
[HERO OF THE SOUTH]
I could serve
my most hidden
confessions to you
on a silver platter,
and you would
never tell a soul.
So I shall confide in you,
and you alone.
There's only one reason
that I have come to be
humanity's strongest hero.
I walk in the present,
yet see the future.
My!
That's quite impressive.
Hm?
You don't believe
I'm telling the truth?
[Frieren blows]
No, I believe you.
I just can't bring myself
to care.
Allow me
to pique your interest,
for the near future holds
much for you and me.
You know of the Seven Sages
of Destruction, yes?
♪
One year from now,
on the Northern Plateau,
I will be slain along with
Schlacht the Omniscient.
They shall rip me
from the world
I have fought
so hard to protect.
♪
Fate has decreed I'm to die
without achieving my goal.
♪
Don't feel sorry for me.
Even if you were to join me
on my journey,
I fear the truth of my demise
is already set in stone.
Forget me.
Soon, a much younger,
sunnier hero
will pay you a visit.
♪
Though, it terribly pains
my soul to admit,
it is he who will save
the world, and not I.
He will successfully
convince you
to travel with his party,
and that party will defeat
the Demon King.
I honestly
can't see that happening.
[HERO OF THE SOUTH]
You'll see once you meet him.
That young man is going to
change your life for good.
♪
Well, then,
the clock is ticking.
Before I go,
may I ask you a favor?
[FRIEREN] What is it?
[HERO OF THE SOUTH]
When you meet that young man,
give him this message.
♪
[HERO OF THE SOUTH]
You have my word.
I will clear a path for you.
Put your faith
in humanity's strongest,
the Hero of the South.
Even if my contributions
are buried
in the shadows of history,
it will be well worth it.
[Stark laughing]
[BOY 1] Hey! Get back here!
[BOY 2] You'll never get away!
[Frieren chuckles softly]
[FRIEREN]
Some foresight you had.
You are as present here as ever.
History hasn't forgotten
a thing.
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN GRAF DACH'S DOMAIN, LOCATED
IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
The last time we were in
a big city was ages ago.
[FRIEREN]
We're leaving as soon as
we replenish our supplies.
Seriously? I'd be okay
with taking it slow.
Hey.
They've even got magic shops.
Summon your focus, Stark.
Don't you know
time is a finite resource?
Yeah, I'm well-aware.
[Fern grunts softly]
♪
Well, that's everything.
Come on.
At least let us grab
something nice to eat
before we leave town.
Not a chance.
We've no coin to spare.
We must be economical,
or our pockets will be empty
when we need them full.
You've sure turned over
a new leaf.
[FRIEREN] Quick. Let's go.
She's been acting strange
this whole time.
[STARK] Something's off.
Normally, she'd want
to stay and explore
a big city like this
for a few months or longer.
But...
We were so close.
You must be
the illustrious Miss Frieren.
My lord has formally invited you
to dinner at his home.
[FRIEREN] We're not hungry.
And we're in a hurry.
It is truly a shame.
He says Miss Frieren was
a member of the party of heroes
that saved this land years ago.
He merely wishes to give
his thanks to all three of you.
[Frieren sighs]
[insects trilling]
[knife slicing softly]
Mm. Now that's what
I'm talkin' about!
[Dach chuckles]
Thank you for
the kind invitation, Graf Dach.
Sincerely.
[FERN] She looks
terribly unhappy.
I should thank you.
You helped my great grandpa.
I'm eternally grateful.
So, what do you want?
[Dach chuckles]
I admire those who can get
straight to the point.
The truth is, my family's
treasured heirloom sword
has been stolen from us
by a demon.
You allowed it
to be stolen again?
Hmm. "Again?"
It was stolen from
his great-grandpa, too.
They just don't live and learn.
[FRIEREN] Very well.
You can reward me
with a grimoire.
Seems like a fair price.
[FRIEREN] What a pain.
I've found many of the nobles
in the northern lands
to be extremely pushy.
But I recall this family
has always made
particularly unreasonable
demands.
If you don't get
my sword back,
I will throw you
in the dungeon.
-[HIMMEL] Huh?
-[EISEN] Talk about tyrannical.
At least they were able
to point us in the direction
that the demon fled
this time around.
We were given no leads before.
The aimlessness of our search
conjures images
of needles and haystacks.
Ultimately,
we did find the sword.
It was at the top
of the Schwer Mountains.
What a waste of energy.
Huh.
I wonder why the demons
have stolen the sword again.
[FRIEREN] The sword wasn't
the Dach Family's originally.
It once belonged
to a famous demon.
It must possess some appeal
only demons understand.
You know, when he mentioned
this job,
I was sure
you would turn it down.
[Frieren inhales
and exhales deeply]
I didn't have a real choice.
This is the very same sword
Himmel retrieved.
If I had let it stay stolen,
his efforts would've been
for naught.
Besides, Himmel wouldn't
abandon someone in need.
♪
We're too late.
It's already been destroyed.
[STARK] There's nobody left.
-[rustling]
-[birds cawing]
No. I can sense one.
Are you from this village?
[WOMAN] No.
I'm a traveling priest.
And who are you?
[STARK] Just adventurers
passing through.
Look around.
This is the work
of the Sword Demon.
I came here to mourn
the innocent lives they stole.
You said "Sword Demon?"
That sounds like the very demon
we came here to slay.
[WOMAN]
The sword demon has destroyed
countless villages
in this region.
There has never been
a single survivor.
[FERN] How awful.
[WOMAN]
Brave adventurers...
Will you offer a prayer
for their souls?
Wait, did I miss something?
[FRIEREN] As I thought,
there are no bodies
buried here.
[FERN] Why not?
Because the traveling priest
is the Sword Demon.
[Fern and Stark gasp]
Not the type to leave corpses,
are you?
I was nearly starving
when I killed them.
I did what I had to do
in order to survive.
[FRIEREN] Even though
you don't have to eat humans?
[SWORD DEMON]
Perhaps I don't have to,
but that doesn't mean
I shouldn't.
[FRIEREN] Speaking to it
is a waste of time.
Destroy it.
[Stark grunting]
[FERN] It's quick.
[Fern gasps]
[Stark grunting]
Thanks for that.
Don't mention it.
It's what I'm here for.
[shivering] So cold.
This was a truly awful job.
Agreed. But at least
we defeated a demon.
[HIMMEL] It was an inconvenience
at the moment.
But down the road,
our efforts today
could save lives.
♪
You never know.
That's why I can't abandon
someone who needs me.
[chuckles] Or maybe your joy
merely grows with our sorrow.
The challenge
is what makes it exciting.
Exciting for who?
Expertly done, you two.
You fired first. Why?
The demon hadn't escalated
the situation at all.
Because I knew you and Stark
were about to pray.
-I had no choice but to act.
-[Fern exclaims softly]
♪
[FRIEREN] Typically,
when people go to pray,
they close their eyes.
The demon knew that
and took advantage of it
to kill and consume
compassionate travelers.
[Stark exclaims softly]
♪
[chuckles]
My treasured heirloom
is home at last.
I'm ever in your debt.
Thanks to you...
our beloved city
is safe once more.
[Frieren chuckles]
[footsteps]
[FRIEREN] Could you please
drop us off at the marketplace?
Why certainly, ma'am.
[FERN] At the end of the day,
the Graf seemed
quite happy with us.
I just hope he keeps a close eye
on his sword.
I have a feeling that
if the demons want it so badly,
they'll try to steal it again.
There's no doubt.
That was the second time
they succeeded.
But the town has faced
many an attack.
[FERN] Hmm?
So as long as the Graf
hangs onto that sword,
the demons will keep trying
to take it back?
I understand
it's a treasured heirloom,
but if it's that dangerous,
maybe they should
get rid of it already.
Unfortunately,
it's not that simple.
Is it not?
I suppose you would know.
Nobles can be so protective
over their riches.
They're stubborn
in that regard.
That much is true.
But if they dispose of it
or send it away,
they risk letting it fall
into the hands of a demon.
[STARK] Hm.
When a demon
acquires power like that,
you can bet
they are going to show it off.
[STARK] Mm.
♪
Is that the nature
of all demons?
The last time a demon
had the sword,
it started out
on a similar rampage.
Three villages were destroyed.
A town was razed to the ground.
That's insane.
The Graf was mortified.
A traitor helped the demon
procure the weapon.
A servant of the Graf
fell for its kind words
and manufactured charm.
♪
[FRIEREN] Ever since then,
Graf Dach's family
has prioritized
protecting the heirloom sword.
[indistinct chatter]
[FRIEREN] Perhaps the mission
has outgrown the family.
It seems to have become
the duty of the whole city.
[STARK] Huh?
You think this demon had help?
Was there a traitor
like last time around?
I'm not sure.
That said,
as long as humankind
knows desire,
the demons will
take advantage of it.
[Stark sighs]
Humans struggle
to resist their impulses.
Much like the demons.
If it happens again,
I hope you come back.
They'll need you.
That shall depend on the reward.
We all know you would
come flying back
for any old grimoire.
[FRIEREN] Who can say?
Though they did give me
an exceptionally interesting one
this time.
[sniffs]
I'm glad, Mistress.
What is it, then?
Something we can really use?
♪
Oh, yes.
A miraculous spell
that can turn
a red apple into
a green one.
[STARK] That's a no, then.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[MAN] This brings me back.
[STARK]
I think I'd like to visit.
[FRIEREN]
You just called me a grandma.
[overlapping chatter]
[HEITER] You promised
it would be quick!
[HIMMEL] There's something here.
[FRIEREN]
"Somewhere She'd Like."